(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-02T22:41:19.253059",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
灼けつくような陽射し
The scorching sunlight,
水面に浮かぶスパンコール
sequins floating on the water's surface.
燥ぐ夏色と逆光の裏側で
Behind the frolicking summer colors and backlighting,
あの日の青春を呼び起こしてる
it's awakening the youth of that day.
デニムの裾を捲って
Rolling up denim hems,
裸足で走ってる砂の上
running barefoot on the sand.
硝子の淵で回り回る 輝く瑠璃色のビー玉
Sparkling lapis lazuli marbles spinning around on the glass edge,
なんだか、その笑顔と紙一重だ
feels like it's a paper-thin difference from that smile.
フィルムを覗けばノンフィクション
Peering through the film, it's non-fiction,
彩りに絆されたメモリー
memories bound by vivid colors.
リセットなんて出来ないから
Because we can't just hit reset,
Love yourself just as you are now
踊ってミッドサマー アルゴリズムの中
Dance in the midsummer, inside the algorithm,
瞬息でダビングして 切り取って喜怒哀楽
dubbing in an instant, cropping every emotion.
これがきっと愛だ
This must surely be love,
二度と忘れないように
so that we'll never forget it again.
Le lemon lime orange キミと一生分の思い出
Le lemon, lime, orange, a lifetime of memories with you.
何気ない一日が one of a kind
A casual day becomes one of a kind.
灼けつくような陽射し
The scorching sunlight,
水面に浮かぶスパンコール
sequins floating on the water's surface.
燥ぐ夏色と逆光の裏側で
Behind the frolicking summer colors and backlighting,
あの日の青春を呼び起こしてる
it's awakening the youth of that day.
デニムの裾を捲って
Rolling up denim hems,
裸足で走ってる砂の上
running barefoot on the sand.
硝子の淵で回り回る 輝く瑠璃色のビー玉
Sparkling lapis lazuli marbles spinning around on the glass edge,
なんだか、その笑顔と紙一重だ
feels like it's a paper-thin difference from that smile.
フィルムを覗けばノンフィクション
Peering through the film, it's non-fiction,
彩りに絆されたメモリー
memories bound by vivid colors.
リセットなんて出来ないから
Because we can't just hit reset,
Love yourself just as you are now
踊ってミッドサマー アルゴリズムの中
Dance in the midsummer, inside the algorithm,
瞬息でダビングして
dubbing in an instant,
切り取って喜怒哀楽
cropping every emotion.
これがきっと愛だ
This must surely be love,
二度と忘れないように
so that we'll never forget it again.
Le Lemon Lime Orange キミと一生分の思い出
Le Lemon Lime Orange, a lifetime of memories with you.
何気ない一日が One of a kind
A casual day becomes one of a kind.
氷が溶けては渦巻いた
The ice melts and swirls,
魔法の杖がわりのマドラー
a muddler acting as a magic wand.
喉の奥くすぐる炭酸
Carbonation tickling the back of the throat,
香る柑橘系のフレイバー
a fragrant citrus flavor.
爽やかな気流にのって
Riding on a refreshing air current,
波の還りを見守ってる Beachside
watching over the returning waves at the beachside.
あどけない面影に焦がれ
Yearning for that innocent face,
微かに触れそうな指先
fingertips almost touching slightly.
煌めきで上塗りしてしまおう
Let me paint over it with sparkle,
Get ahead of what you used to be
踊ってミッドサマー アルゴリズムの中
Dance in the midsummer, inside the algorithm,
瞬息でダビングして
dubbing in an instant,
切り取って喜怒哀楽
cropping every emotion.
これがきっと愛だ
This must surely be love,
二度と忘れないように
so that we'll never forget it again.
ミッドサマーシトラス Oh yeah
Midsummer Citrus, oh yeah!
いつだって We got love!! Okay
Always, we got love!! Okay,
キミといるだけで Feel so nice ココロはまた実り
just being with you feels so nice, my heart flourishes again.
寝起きのお太陽も 願ってもない燦々日和？
Even the morning sun brings an unexpectedly radiant day, right?
白飛びしてしまうほど
So bright that it overexposes,
眩しいのは夏のせい
this dazzling light is all because of summer.
踊ってミッドサマー
Dance through midsummer
アルゴリズムの中 (Ooh)
inside the algorithm. (Ooh)
瞬息でダビングして
Dubbing in an instant,
切り取って喜怒哀楽
clipping every emotion.
これがきっと愛だ (Ooh)
This must surely be love. (Ooh)
二度と忘れないように
So we'll never forget it again,
(Oh) Le Lemon Lime Orange
キミと一生分の想い出
a lifetime of memories with you.
(Oh) 何気ない一日が One of a kind
(Oh) A casual day becomes one of a kind.
はい！ じゃあ皆さん、お疲れ様でした〜！
All right! Everyone, great job out there!
せーの！ 位置について... We are ReGLOSS!
Ready, set! Take your positions... We are ReGLOSS!
はい！ じゃあここから自己紹介いよろ〜！
All right! Time for introductions!
振り遅れ知らずのホロライブDEV_IS所属、音乃瀬奏です！ こんにちは〜！
From hololive DEV_IS, never off-beat, I'm Otonose Kanade! Hello!
そして〜！
And next~!
ハイポジティブジーニアス！ ホロライブDEV_IS ReGLOSSの一条莉々華だよ〜！ イエーイ！
High-positive genius! I'm Ichijou Ririka from hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS! Yay!
そして〜！
And next~!
え〜、ブンブンボーン！ ホロライブDEV_IS ReGLOSSの番長、轟はじめ... 始まれ！
Uh, vroom vroom vroom! Hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS's Banchou, Todoroki Hajime... Let's get started!
はい、ホロライブDEV_IS ReGLOSSの賑やかシネマトーク担当、重定一真... 全然違ーい！ 儒烏風亭らでん でございます！
Yes, hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS's lively cinema talk representative, Juusada Kazuma... Totally wrong! I'm Juufuutei Raden!
イエーイ！
Yay!
いきなりですが、なんと新曲をお披露目させていただきました！
Out of nowhere, we just performed our new song for the first time!
イエーイ！
Yay!
みんなどうだったー？
How was it, everyone?
最初のさ...
At the beginning...
本当にごめんなさい！
I'm really sorry!
本当に... 本当に申し訳ない！
I'm so... I'm deeply sorry!
もう最初さー、あの、これぜひアーカイブで見返してほしいんですけれども...
Right at the start, um, I really want you to rewatch the archive, but...
我々が、あの、足でジャンケンをする...
...where we play rock-paper-scissors with our feet...
そう、あっち向いてホイをするシーンがあるんだよね！
Yeah, the scene where we play "Look That Way, Hoi!", right?
そうそう。そこで、あの、事前の打ち合わせと...
Exactly. Right there, what we pre-arranged...
違うものが出ちゃった！
...something totally different came out!
あっち向いてホイをするっていうのに...
Even though we were supposed to do "Look That Way, Hoi!"...
しかも一回もあっち向いてホイ成功しなかったけど、なんか... 勝ったことになってて...
...and not once did it succeed, somehow... it ended up counting as a win...
みんなも、リリカも笑ってるし！ でもソロパート頑張らなきゃって思ったら、余計声ビリビリ震えてた！
Everyone, including me, was laughing! But when I thought "I gotta do my solo part right", my voice started shaking even more!
笑い声聞こえちゃってたのかな？
Could they hear us laughing?
コメント欄見えて、「笑ってるやん」って！
I looked at the comments and saw "They're laughing!"
そう、実はね、そんなこんながあったんです！
Yeah, actually, that's what happened!
けれどまあ、そんなこんなも含めてね、生配信、ライブの醍醐味でございます！
But well, including all of that, that's the real charm of a live stream!
そうですねー！ 1回目だから...
That's right! Since it was the first time...
1回目だからバレてないやろ。ああいうのだと誤魔化せてるかもしれない。
Since it's the first time, maybe they didn't catch on. We might have pulled it off.
バレる、バレる！
They definitely noticed!
はい、それでね、こんな『ミッドサマーシトラス』なんですが...
Anyway, about "Midsummer Citrus"...
なんと、もう既にね、MVが公開されております！
Believe it or not, the MV is already out!
イエーイ！ 見た〜！
Yay! We watched it~!
せっかくなんでね、一人ずつ感想聞いていきますか！
Since we're here, shall we hear everyone's thoughts one by one?
じゃあ番長から！
Let's start with Banchou!
え〜、なんかやっぱ夏って言ったらこう、ハッピーハッピーって感じなのかなって思ったら...
Well, I thought summer meant like, a happy-happy vibe... but!
ちょっとこう、ノスタルジックな...
It's a bit nostalgic...
ちょっとエモい感じの過去を彷彿とさせる...
...with a slightly emotional feel that brings back the past...
いい夏の思い出、みたいな感じで、エモい、いい曲だな〜って思いました！
...like a nice summer memory. I thought it was a really great, emotional song!
いいこと言うじゃん！
Well said!
奏は？
What about Kanade?
奏は〜、やっぱりこう、制服着てたりしてたから、学生時代のことを...
For me, since we were wearing uniforms, it made me think of my school days...
やっぱり思い出したりしたし、あとすごい爽やかな夏曲だったから...
...and since it's such a refreshing summer song...
外に出てね、暑い夏の時に聴きながら道を歩いてたら涼しくなるのかな〜って思いました！
...I felt like if you listen to it while walking outside on a hot summer day, it'd cool you down!
いっぱい聴いてください！
Please listen to it a lot!
いいですね〜！
That's great~!
リリカはね、なんかMVにやっぱり私たちのカット、青含めてね...
For me, the MV had so many shots of us, including Ao-chan...
ReGLOSSのカットが沢山入ってて...
...so many shots of ReGLOSS in it...
なんかそれを見ているだけでちょっとニヤニヤしちゃった！
...that just watching it made me grin!
可愛い〜！
So cute~!
奏がすごいリリカのこと凝視してるところ...
The part where Kanade was staring super hard at me...
隣で見つめてた！
I was staring right next to you!
でもよくやってる、それは！
But you actually do that all the time!
奏はね、リリカのことガン見してるから...
Kanade always stares right at Ririka...
再現されてるそうです！ なので色々ね、細かいところ是非皆さんも見てみてください！
...so that was faithfully recreated! Please check out all the fine details, everyone!
ください！ そして、あの、このね、サビの冒頭...
Please do! And also, at the beginning of the chorus...
『踊ってミッドサマー』ってある通り、こういうところとかね！
...as the lyrics say "Dance through midsummer", parts like this!
みんなでウォ〜ウォ〜ウォ〜って言うところとか...
Where everyone goes "Woah woah woah"...
すごくノリやすくて、踊りやすい曲なんじゃないかなと思いますんで...
...it's super catchy and easy to dance to, so...
是非皆さんも踊ってミッドサマーやってみてください！
...please try dancing through midsummer yourselves!
宜しくお願いします！
Please check it out!
え〜、ということで、今回ね、MVに関わってくださった監督、クリエイターの皆様...
So, to the director and creators who worked on this MV...
素敵に撮影してくださって本当にありがとうございました！
...thank you so much for filming us so beautifully!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
え〜、そして、ついに！ ついに！
And finally! Finally!
明日0時！ つまり... 今日の24時に...
Tomorrow at 0:00! Meaning... at 24:00 today...
こちらね、『ミッドサマーシトラス』デジタルリリースされます！
...'Midsummer Citrus' will be released digitally!
イエーイ！
Yay!
だから日付が変わったタイミングですね！
So right at midnight when the date changes!
ReGLOSSと言えばお馴染みの...
Speaking of ReGLOSS, the familiar...
オートラさん
Otorasan,
舞島爽さんに手がけていただいた
with composition by Soushi Maishima,
爽やかなメロディーと
is a song with a refreshing melody
心地よいリズムが
and a pleasant rhythm
夏の暑さを吹き飛ばしてくれるような
that blows away the summer heat!
1曲でございます！
It's a wonderful track!
ぜひこの夏は『Midsummer Citrus』を聴いて
Be sure to listen to "Midsummer Citrus" this summer
ReGLOSSとの夏の思い出をたくさん作りましょう！
and make lots of summer memories with ReGLOSS!
作りましょう！
Let me make memories!
ということで、今日はここからまた別の夏曲を歌っていこうと思うんですけれども
So today, we're going to sing other summer songs!
事前にアンケートでみんなに応募してもらった
We'll also be singing the songs you requested
曲も歌いますので、楽しみに待っていてください！
in our survey, so look forward to it!
はーい！
Yay!
じゃ、ちょっと真夏のビーチということで、あまりにも暑くて倒れてしまいそうなので、移動しますか！
Since we're on a midsummer beach and it's so hot we might pass out, shall we move?
あ、待って、足熱い熱い！
Wait, my feet are so hot!
熱っ！熱っ！
Hot, hot, hot!
あ、熱い熱い熱い！
It's hot, hot, hot!
しばらくお待ちください
[Please wait a moment]
強制カットや！
Forced cut!
やっちまったー！
We blew it!
何もやっちまってないよー！
We didn't blow anything!
カラオケ向かいますからね！
We're heading to karaoke!
カラオケ行こう行こう！
Let's go to karaoke!
カラオケだって歌うんだからね！
We're gonna sing at karaoke!
会員証持ってる？
Do you have a membership card?
アプリダウンロードしてないかも
I might not have downloaded the app...
あ、カードで持ってるから大丈夫！
Oh, I have a physical card, so it's fine!
何歌おうかなー
What should I sing?
悩むね！
Hard to choose!
今回リクエストをいただいておりますから！
We received requests this time!
みんなのリクエストした曲が入ってるかもしれないね
Your requested song might be in there!
『Midsummer Citrus』？歌ったばっかりなのに！
"Midsummer Citrus"? We just sang that!
じゃんけんのやり直しから！
Let me redo the rock-paper-scissors!
最初はい、じゃんけんぽん！
Rock, paper, scissors, go!
いいところでやるじゃん！
Nice timing!
ポスターある！
There's a poster!
あ、ポスター？
Wait, a poster?
急にポスター出てきたからびっくりした！
It surprised me when a poster suddenly appeared!
あるわけないじゃん！
Why wouldn't there be one?
ドリンク買いに行ってくるけど何が良い？
I'm going to buy drinks, what do you want?
コーンスープとカルピス2個欲しい
I want corn soup and two Calpis!
じゃ、ウーロン茶！
Oolong tea for me!
全部の上にソフトクリーム乗せてきて
Put soft-serve ice cream on top of all of them.
なんでだよ！乗せなくていいから！
Why?! Don't do that!
戻ったー！
I'm back!
時間もないので早速歌っていこうと思います！
We don't have much time, so let's start singing!
何の歌を歌うのかな、楽しみだね！
I wonder what song it will be, so exciting!
一番最初に歌いたい人は誰ですか？
Who wants to sing first?
はい！
Me!
番長！行くじゃん！
Boss! Go for it!
スタート一発目この元気良さで行ける人なかなかいないよ
Not many people can kick off with this much energy!
夏を盛り上げていこうじゃん！
Let's hype up the summer!
番長からいきましょう！
Let's start with Boss!
お願いしまーす！
Here we go!
「サンオイル 背中に塗って！」と
"Put sunscreen on my back," you said,
水着の上 外しながら寝そべった
and lay sprawled out, unfastening your swimsuit top.
大胆な君の一言は
Those bold words of yours
甘ったるい 匂いがした
had a sweet, sugary scent.
どこまでも青い海と空
The endless blue sea and sky
僕たちの関係に似てる
resemble our relationship.
水平線は 交わってるのに
Though they meet at the horizon,
そう 今はまだ わがままな妹のようさ
yes, right now you're still like a willful little sister.
真夏のSounds good ! つぶやきながら
Whispering "Summer's Sounds good!",
次のステップへ進みたいね 恋のカリキュラム
I want to take the next step in love's curriculum.
波音 Sounds good ! 心が騒ぐよ
The sound of waves sounds good! My heart is stirred.
去年よりも 僕本気になる
This year, I'm more serious than last year.
砂浜で肌を灼いている
Tanning your skin on the sandy beach,
君を置いて 僕一人泳いだよ
I left you there and went swimming alone.
僕は一人泳いだよ
I swam alone in the sea
その後のいきなりのキスは 塩辛い味がした
The sudden kiss after that tasted salty
さっきまでのあの風景とは
Compared to the scenery from just earlier,
空気まで変わった気がする
I feel like even the air has changed
海と空がちゃんと向き合って
The sea and sky face each other properly,
そうお互いのその青さ 映し合っている
reflecting each other's shade of blue
渚のGood job! 愛しい人よ
Good job at the shore! My beloved one
ずっと切なくて言えなかった 君が近すぎて
It was so bittersweet I couldn't say it, you were too close
きっかけGood job! 素直になるんだ
Good job for the spark! I'll be honest
手を伸ばそう 恋の季節じゃないか！
Let me reach out my hand, isn't it the season of love?
真夏のSounds good! つぶやきながら
Midsummer Sounds good! Whispering as I go
次のステップへ進みたいね 恋のカリキュラム
I want to move on to the next step in love's curriculum
波音Sounds good! 心が騒ぐよ
Sound of waves Sounds good! My heart gets excited
去年よりも僕は本気になる
I'm getting more serious than last year
真夏のSounds good! 君が好きだ 波音Sounds good!
Midsummer Sounds good! I like you, sound of waves Sounds good!
やっと言えたよ 渚のGood job! 君が好きだ
I finally said it! Good job at the shore! I like you
きっかけGood job! いいタイミングだね
Good job for the spark! Perfect timing
真夏のSounds good!
Midsummer Sounds good!
1曲目からぶち上がっていくー！
Hyping it up right from the very first song!
あー、いい曲ですね。なんか枝豆とビールもらってきて宜しく。
Ah, what a good song. Could someone fetch me some edamame and beer?
おじさんのお酒のモードか！ちょっとおじさん入れちゃった？
Are you in old man drinking mode? Did you unleash an old man?
ちょっとキラキラしすぎちゃって、おじさん入れておきますね。
It was a bit too idol-sparkly, so I brought out the old man inside.
ちなみに何でこの曲にしたの？
By the way, why did you pick this song?
なんかアンケートにあって、歌えるでチェックを入れた。
It was on the survey form, so I checked "can sing".
もうちょっとあるでしょ！こういうところが好きなの。
Surely there's more to it! But I love that about you.
でもすごいじゃん。白い砂浜、青い空、白いビキニの美少女たちが「きゃー」って言ってる姿が浮かんでくるのが素敵じゃないですか。
But it was great! White sandy beach, blue sky, pretty girls in white bikinis going "kyaa"—isn't that image lovely?
夏っぽかった！しかも盛り上がるね。ノリノリだった今。
It felt so summery! And it gets everyone hyped. You were totally in the groove.
ダンスも準備してきたの？
Did you prepare the dance moves too?
いや、ノリで... 本家のダンスと別にあって、それは覚えてきてないですけど、即興で。
No, just on pure vibe... The official dance is different, and I didn't memorize that, so it was improvised.
すごーい！プロだったよ！
Amazing! You looked like a total pro!
素晴らしい！次、次行く？
Wonderful! Next, shall we move on to the next person?
この後歌いたい人いるわけないじゃん！なんでー？
No way anyone wants to sing after that! Why?!
でも一応台本だと奏になってるけど... 無理だよー！
Though according to the script, Kanade is next... No way I can follow that!
頑張れー！カラオケ準備大丈夫？音楽お願いします、いつものあれ下さい！
Good luck! Ready for karaoke? Music please, give me the usual!
少女レイ
[Title: Shoujo Rei]
可愛いー！ファンサしてくれる！
So cute! She's giving us fan service!
本能が狂い始める 追い詰められたハツカネズミ
Instinct begins to go mad, a cornered mouse
今 絶望の淵に立って 踏切へと飛び出した
Now standing on the edge of despair, leaping onto the railroad crossing
そう 君は友達 僕の手を掴めよ そう 君は独りさ 居場所なんて無いだろ
Yes, you're a friend, grab my hand; Yes, you're alone, you have no place to belong
居場所なんて無いだろ
You have no place to belong
二人きりこのまま 愛し合えるさー
Just the two of us as we are, we can love each other...
繰り返し フラッシュバック 蝉の声 二度とは帰らぬ君
Repeating flashback, the sound of cicadas, you who will never return
永遠に千切れてく お揃いのキーホルダー
Forever torn apart, our matching keyholders
夏が消し去った 白い肌の少女に
To the girl with white skin that summer erased,
哀しい程 とり憑かれて仕舞いたい
I want to be haunted to a sorrowful degree
いやー最高！ありがとう！
Woah, that was awesome! Thank you!
本性が暴れ始める
One's true nature begins to rage
九月のスタート 告げるチャイム
The chime signaling the start of September
次の標的に置かれた花瓶 仕掛けたのは僕だった
The vase placed on the next target, I was the one who set it
そう 君が悪いんだよ 僕だけを見ててよ
Yes, you are the bad one, look only at me
そう 君の苦しみ 助けが欲しいだろ
Yes, your suffering, you want help, right?
溺れてく其の手に そっと口吻(kiss)をしたー
I softly kissed those drowning hands...
薄笑いの獣たち その心晴れるまで
The faintly smiling beasts, until their minds clear
爪を突き立てる 不揃いのスカート
Digging in their claws, mismatched skirts
夏の静寂を 切り裂くような悲鳴が 酵する教室の窓には青空
A scream cutting through the summer silence, in the window of the echoing classroom is the blue sky
なんか雰囲気やってる！一人雰囲気やってる！
Someone's getting into character! One person's getting into character!
あ、すごい！
Ah, awesome!
服の色も黄色だから合ってる！
Her clothes are yellow too, so it matches!
君はあたま...
You're...
そう 君は友達 僕の手を掴めよ
Yes, you are a friend, take my hand
そう 君が居なくちゃ 居場所なんて無いんだよ
Yes, if you're not here, I have no place to belong
透き通った世界で 愛し合えたらー
If only we could love each other in a transparent world...
繰り返し フラッシュバック 蝉の声 二度とは帰らぬ君
Repeating flashback, the sound of cicadas, you who will never return
永遠に千切れてく お揃いのキーホルダー
Forever torn apart, our matching keyholders
夏が消し去った 白い肌の少女に
To the girl with white skin that summer erased,
哀しい程 とり憑かれて仕舞いたい
I want to be haunted to a sorrowful degree
透明な君は 僕を指差してたー
The transparent you was pointing at me...
ありがとうございましたー！ 音乃瀬奏でしたー！
Thank you so much! I was Otonose Kanade!
一気にエモい気分になったり
I suddenly felt so emotional.
奏のやっぱ綺麗なさ 澄み通るような声にめちゃくちゃ合ってる曲だよね
This song really suits Kanade's clean, crystal-clear voice so well.
やったー！嬉しい！
Yay! I'm so happy!
アンケートでもね 奏にぜひ歌ってほしいっていうのあったみたいだよ
In the survey too, it seems a lot of people wanted Kanade to sing this.
センス良い！ナイス選曲！最高！
Great taste! Nice choice! Awesome!
そのコメントした人...
The person who made that comment...
これ奏の後も 相当なハードル上がってるんですけどー
Coming after Kanade is setting the bar really high...
じゃあ 帰りますね
Well then, I'm heading home.
ちょっと待って！まだ帰らないでー！
Wait a minute! Don't leave yet!
もう今奏に選ばれてちょっとドキドキしてるし
Now that Kanade chose me, I'm feeling a bit nervous.
次は選ばれた方のお歌じゃないですか？
Isn't it time for the chosen one to sing next?
おー！いけー！楽しく歌おう！
Ooh! Go for it! Let's sing with fun!
うん じゃあ行きます！お願いします！
Yup, here I go! Wish me luck!
煌めいて 揺らめいて
Sparkling and swaying,
蒼き夢 舞い放つ
releasing a blue dream,
花燃えゆく
the flowers burn bright.
静寂に落ちる空
The sky falls into silence,
ふたひらの夢花火
two-petaled dream fireworks.
彼方に旅立つ
Departing into the distance,
あなたも見えたの？ 同じ光が
could you see it too? That same light.
離れてもいつの日か
Even if we are apart,
出逢えると信じてる
I believe we will meet again someday.
胸裂く想いをあなたに
My heart-rending feelings for you...
歌うわ声が聴こえる？
I will sing them out, can you hear my voice?
せつなにひらくそれは HANABI
Blooming for just a moment, that is HANABI.
煌めいて 揺らめいて
Sparkling and swaying,
蒼き夢 舞い放つ
releasing a blue dream,
咲き誇れ 遥か高く
bloom proudly, far and high.
守りゆくその想い
These feelings I will protect,
ひたすら鳴り響け
resound incessantly.
果てるまで せめて強く
Until the end, at least stay strong.
此の花燃えゆく
This flower burns bright.
いくつもの言の葉を
Countless words of mine,
悪戯に散らかした
scattered away playfully.
断ちゆく迷いは
The hesitations being severed,
静かに消えたの
quietly disappeared.
明日が見えてる？
Can you see tomorrow?
せつなにひらくそれは HANABI
Blooming for just a moment, that is HANABI.
煌めいて 揺らめいて
Sparkling and swaying,
つかみゆく幻の花
a fleeting flower reached for,
あたしの手を零れ落ちて
slips through my hands and falls.
願うままこの想い
May these feelings, as wished,
あなたに鳴り渡れ
echo through to you.
果てるならせめて強く
If it must end, at least be strong.
此の花燃えゆく
This flower burns bright.
せつなにひらくそれは HANABI
Blooming for just a moment, that is HANABI.
煌めいて 揺らめいて
Sparkling and swaying,
蒼き夢 舞い上がれ
soar high, blue dream.
いつの日かめぐり逢えて
Meeting again by chance someday,
繋ぎゆくこの想い
connecting these feelings,
愛しき君 我
beloved you and me.
いつまでも双片強く
Forever, both petals strong.
煌めいて 揺らめいて
Sparkling and swaying,
蒼き夢 舞い放つ
releasing a blue dream,
咲き誇れ 遥か高く
bloom proudly, far and high.
守りゆくその想い
These feelings I will protect,
ひたすら鳴り響け
resound incessantly.
果てるまで せめて強く
Until the end, at least stay strong.
此の花燃えゆく
This flower burns bright.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
めっちゃよかった！
That was so good!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
すごいなんか、リリカに合ってる！
It really fits Ririka so well!
この曲合ってる！
This song really suits you!
え、めっちゃ嬉しい！
Wow, I'm so glad!
これすごい大好きなアニメの、BLEACHの曲なんだけど
This is an anime song from BLEACH, which I love so much...
あ、そうなんだ！
Oh, really?
そう、いっぱい聴いてた曲だったから、歌いたかったの
Yeah, I listened to it all the time, so I really wanted to sing it!
いいね！
That's awesome!
いいじゃんいいじゃん！
That's great, that's great!
嬉しかったー！
I'm so glad!
でも ってことは次は ラデンちゃんの番...
Which means next is Raden-chan's turn...
ってことは次はラデンちゃんの番！
Which means next is Raden-chan's turn!
「ワンチャン？」「君だよ！」
"Is there a chance?" "It's you!"
じゃあ ちょっとここでまた 盛り上がる系の曲を...
So, I think I'll pick another hype song here...
いこうかなと思います！ / おおー！楽しみ！
I think I'll go with this one! / Awesome! Can't wait!
さあ、チャット欄の皆さん ENJOYの準備をお願いします！
Alright everyone in the chat, get ready to ENJOY!
それではいきましょう！準備OKです！
Here we go! Everything is ready!
よろしくお願いします！
Here goes nothing!
いきますよ！ココロオドル！みんな一緒に盛り上がってください！
Here we go! Kokoro Odoru! Get hyped everyone!
ENJOY 音楽は鳴り続ける
ENJOY, the music keeps playing
IT'S JOIN 届けたい胸の鼓動
IT'S JOIN, sending the heart's pulsation
ココロオドル アンコールわかす
My heart dances, heating up the encore
Dance Dance Dance (READY GO!)
今 ゴーイング ゴールインより
Now going, rather than crossing the finish line,
飛び越し 音に乗り 泳ぎ続ける
leaping over and riding the beat, swimming on.
ENJOY (ENJOY) IT'S JOIN (IT'S JOIN)
呼応する心 響き続ける
Resonating hearts keep echoing.
のってきた的な 言葉が出てきた
Rhythmic words start flowing out,
ここは 心躍るところだから
'cause this is where the heart dances.
置いてかないよ 追い付きたいなら
I won't leave you behind, if you wanna catch up,
Get Up Stand Up 行くしかねぇ
Get Up Stand Up, you've gotta go!
つかねぇやっぱ 気付いたんだ100%
Man, I realized it 100%,
幸せの意思表示 鳴らせ CLAP CLAP
a declaration of happiness, sound it out, CLAP CLAP!
仲間同士 夜通し 詰め込んだ
Comrades together, packed in all night,
アッパーなテンションの シチュエーション
a high-tension situation.
Have a dreamin' グリーディング
Have a dreamin' greeting,
この場の空気 中心 サークル 繋がる ブギー
centered in this room's vibe, a connected boogie circle.
フリーキー きばらず ここのみんなと
Freaky, staying relaxed with everyone here,
その価値あるから Swing swing sing a song
there's value in it, so Swing swing sing a song.
生真面目 恥ずかしがりでもできる
Even if you're serious or shy, you can do it,
イマジネーション 望むところだ
imagination is just what I want.
茶の間 床の間 ところ構わず
Living room, alcove, anywhere goes,
ボタンひとつで 踊る心が
with just one button, the dancing heart...
ENJOY 音楽は鳴り続ける
ENJOY, the music keeps playing
IT'S JOIN 届けたい胸の鼓動
IT'S JOIN, sending the heart's pulsation
ココロオドル アンコールわかす
My heart dances, heating up the encore
Dance Dance Dance (READY GO!)
今 ゴーイング ゴールインより
Now going, rather than crossing the finish line,
飛び越し 音に乗り 泳ぎ続ける
leaping over and riding the beat, swimming on.
ENJOY (ENJOY) IT'S JOIN (IT'S JOIN)
呼応する心 響き続ける
Resonating hearts keep echoing.
やっぱりな Hurry up 俺は急いで歯を磨く
Just as I thought, Hurry up, I hurriedly brush my teeth,
手間は取らせん さぁ見な
won't keep you long, now watch.
あみ出す つぅか 勝手 心騒ぎ出す
Devising a plan, or rather, my heart gets excited,
時間 場所など 限らず
no limits on time or place.
グータラ てきぱき 日常 メリハリ
Lazy or snappy, everyday life's sharp contrast,
毎日変わる音 フレッシュ デリバリー
sounds changing daily, fresh delivery.
揺らす Body Rock 増々
Shaking Body Rock more and more,
ベクトル向かう 矛先はプラスへ
the vector pointing straight toward the positive.
その長と短 そこがどうかなる
Strengths and weaknesses, how will they work out?
所々 ココロゴト 転がり合う
Here and there, rolling together with all our hearts.
だから今日は今日 振り切る昨日
So today is today, shaking off yesterday,
心から踊らす このひと時
dancing from the heart in this moment.
一度 Go ドア開けたら フロア
Once you go, open the door and it's the floor,
浮き足立つ 抜け出す 揺れる Core
restless, breaking out, shaking Core.
Up and down こっち タンタ Tap Let's Dance
Up and down over here, Tanta Tap Let's Dance,
Come on 加速 構うもんか もう
Come on, accelerate, who cares anymore?
いてもたってもいられない
Can't stand sitting still,
心だけじゃ 収まんないぜ
my heart alone can't contain it!
Day and Night Shake a body
ぎこちないなら ないで
clumsy or not,
可愛い 心感じるままに
cute, just feel it from the heart.
LA LA LA LIVE LIVE GOOD TO BE ALIVE
笑い 愛し合いされ 喜怒哀楽 刻む
laughing, loving and loved, carving joy and grief.
音と言葉 つなぐこの場
Music and words connecting this place,
届いてるなら MAKE SOME NOISE
if it's reaching you, MAKE SOME NOISE!
ENJOY 音楽は鳴り続ける
ENJOY, the music keeps playing
IT'S JOIN 届けたい胸の鼓動
IT'S JOIN, sending the heart's pulsation
ココロオドル アンコールわかす
My heart dances, heating up the encore
Dance Dance Dance (READY GO!)
今 ゴーイング ゴールインより
Now going, rather than crossing the finish line,
飛び越し 音に乗り 泳ぎ続ける
leaping over and riding the beat, swimming on.
ENJOY (ENJOY) IT'S JOIN (IT'S JOIN)
呼応する心 響き続ける
Resonating hearts keep echoing.
グレートフル 絵描く スケールはでかく
Painting a grateful picture, the scale is huge,
楽しいもんだ エラク デラックス
it's fun, super deluxe.
狙う暇なんか 単純に簡単
Time to aim is simply easy,
預けて カウントダウン 3・2・1
hand it over, countdown 3, 2, 1.
なりふり構わず 夢中で駆け抜けろ
Disregarding appearances, dash through frantically,
息まいて It's like this
bracing yourself, It's like this.
さらに深い感動へ モーレツ Oh yes
Toward even deeper emotion, intense Oh yes,
ココロオドル 今日へ
my heart dances toward today!
さあ！最後！サビです！チャット欄の皆さん、みんなで一緒に盛り上がってください！
Alright! Last chorus! Everyone in the chat, let me hear you get hyped together!
今 ゴーイング ゴールインより
Now going, rather than crossing the finish line,
飛び越し 音に乗り 泳ぎ続ける
leaping over and riding the beat, swimming on.
ENJOY 音楽は鳴り続ける
ENJOY, the music keeps playing
IT'S JOIN 届けたい胸の鼓動
IT'S JOIN, sending the heart's pulsation
ココロオドル アンコールわかす
My heart dances, heating up the encore
Dance Dance Dance (READY GO!)
今 ゴーイング ゴールインより
Now going, rather than crossing the finish line,
飛び越し 音に乗り 泳ぎ続ける
leaping over and riding the beat, swimming on.
ENJOY (ENJOY) IT'S JOIN (IT'S JOIN)
呼応する心 響き続ける
Resonating hearts keep echoing.
ココロオドル アンコールわかす
My heart dances, heating up the encore
Dance Dance Dance (READY GO!)
今 ゴーイング ゴールインより
Now going, rather than crossing the finish line,
飛び越し 音に乗り 泳ぎ続ける
leaping over and riding the beat, swimming on.
ENJOY (ENJOY) IT'S JOIN (IT'S JOIN)
呼応する心 響き続ける
Resonating hearts keep echoing.
Yeah~! 最高！ありがとうございました！
Yeah~! Awesome! Thank you so much!
以上！儒烏風亭らでんでした！
That's all from Juufuutei Raden!
かっこいい！ / 最高！
So cool! / That was awesome!
ココロオドっちゃったわ！ / 楽しい曲だー！
My heart really danced! / What a fun song!
一人で歌う曲ではないのよ！
That's not a song meant for one person to sing solo...
それはほんとにそう！でもすごいね！
That's so true! But you were amazing!
歌いきったよ！ / すごいエネルギー感じたもん今！
She sang the whole thing! / I could feel so much energy just now!
もう歌えない... / まだまだこれから！
I can't sing anymore... / We're just getting started!
これで…まだ1周しかしてないですけれど…
With this... we've only gone around once, but...
じゃあどうする？
So what now?
じゃあ次誰歌う？
So who's singing next?
次は一ちゃんに歌ってもらうか！
Let's have Icchan sing next!
えー！番長ー！
Eh?! Bancho?!
一長ー！
Iccho~!
なんだろう？いいよ、じゃあ番長の選曲に任せるわ！
What is it? Okay, I'll leave it to Bancho's choice!
いいセンスで！オッケーオッケー！
Pick something with great taste! Okay, okay!
オッケー！じゃあ準備オッケー？
Okay! Are you two ready?
うん！
Yep!
はい！お願いしまーす！
Yes! Let's do this!
おー！いい曲きたー！
Oh! Such a classic song!
テンション上げていくよー！
Let's get hyped up!
イケナイ太陽 (Na Na Na...)
Naughty Sun (Na Na Na...)
チョットでいいから 見せてくれないか / お前のセクシー・フェロモンで オレ メロメロ
Show me, just a little bit / Your sexy pheromones make me mellow
Ah ふれちゃいそう でも イケナイの! / 徐々に高なる鼓動 止められないわ
Ah, I can almost touch, but I shouldn't! / I can't stop my heart beating faster and faster
交わす言葉の記憶遠く / 口元の動きに揺れ動く
Memories of the words we exchanged grow distant / The movement of your lips makes me tremble
濡れた髪を撫でた そして Ah
I stroked your wet hair and then, Ah
ABC 続かない そんなんじゃダメじゃない / だって ココロの奥は 違うんじゃない?
ABC doesn't go any further, that's just no good / 'Cause what's inside our hearts is different, right?
オレの青春 そんなもんじゃない / 熱く奥で果てたいよ
My youth's better than that / I wanna climax deep inside that heat
きっと キミじゃなきゃ やだよ / オレは イケナイ太陽
I know it's gotta be you / I'm a naughty sun
(Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na...)
「赤い糸」なんて 絵空事 / でも下心でさえ 信じたいの
The "red thread" is just a fantasy / But even with my ulterior motives, I want to believe
俺は正しい キミも正しい / とにかくもう 左右されないぜ
I'm right, and you're right, too / Anyway, I won't be swayed anymore
騙し騙され胸うずく / 下手な芝居が より盛り上げる夜
My heart aches as we deceive each other / This bad acting makes the night even more exciting
息が耳に触れた二人 Ah
Our breath touching each other's ears, Ah
ABC 続かない そんなんじゃダメじゃない / だって ココロの奥は 違うんじゃない?
ABC doesn't go any further, that's just no good / 'Cause what's inside our hearts is different, right?
あたしの青春 そんなもんじゃない / 熱く奥で果てたいよ
My youth's better than that / I wanna climax deep inside that heat
きっと キミじゃなきゃ やだよ / あたし イケナイ太陽
I know it's gotta be you / I'm a naughty sun
(Hoo... Hoo... / Na Na Na...)
交わす言葉の記憶遠く / 口元の動きに揺れ動く / 濡れた髪を撫でた そして Ah
Memories of the words we exchanged grow distant / The movement of your lips makes me tremble / I stroked your wet hair and then, Ah
ABC ABC 続かない / そんなんじゃダメじゃない / だって ココロの奥は 違うんじゃない?
ABC ABC doesn't go any further / That's just no good / 'Cause what's inside our hearts is different, right?
オレの青春 そんなもんじゃない / 熱く奥で果てたいよ / きっと キミじゃなきゃ やだよ
My youth's better than that / I wanna climax deep inside that heat / I know it's gotta be you
オレは イケナイ太陽
I'm a naughty sun
絡み合う糸は / 君と俺を結ぶ赤い糸
The intertwining thread / Is the red thread binding you and me
(Na Na Na Na Na Na Na Na...)
あー疲れたー！最高！
Ah, I'm tired! That was awesome!
いやこの曲番長のセクシーがあふれ出てていいですね！
Man, Bancho's sexiness was really overflowing in this song, it was great!
ちょっとアチアチになりましたね！
It got pretty hot in here!
アチアチだねー！
Sure is hot!
社長の動きも激熱でした！
Shacho's dance moves were super intense too!
俺お前おど...歌なんだから！
I was supposed to be singing, you know!
踊りかい！ってね！楽しかったー！
More like dancing! But yeah, that was so much fun!
平成ですね、さっきから！
It's been so Heisei era since earlier!
令和の曲わかんなくなってきたな...
I'm starting to not recognize Reiwa songs anymore...
選曲も続きますよ！
The song selection continues!
かなでとらでんの出番なんじゃないの？
Isn't it Kanade and Raden's turn?
え？いいじゃん
Eh? Sounds good!
ちょっとこう結構ね ヒートアップしちゃったから 一旦クールダウンしようかね
It got pretty heated up, so let's cool down for a bit.
よしっ！
Alright!
らでんの体力も持ちませんから
Because Raden's stamina won't hold up either!
ちょっとゆったりした曲をね
Let me do a slightly calm song.
はい、じゃあ2人とも準備してくださいね
Okay, then both of you get ready.
はーい
Okaay!
よっこいしょ
Up we go.
準備いいですか？ はい！
Are you ready? Yes!
はい！ あれ、座って歌う？
Yes! Wait, are you sitting down to sing?
いや、立つ！
No, standing!
あ、立ってるか！
Ah, you're standing!
立ってるな！
Standing!
心が踊ってきた！
My heart started dancing!
では、音楽をお願いします！
Then, music please!
踊っちゃダメよ
Don't dance!
夕月夜 顔だす 消えてく子供の声
The evening moon shows its face, as children's voices fade away.
遠く遠くこの空のどこかに 君はいるんだろう
Somewhere far, far away in this sky, you must be there.
夏の終わりに 2人で抜け出した
Sneaking out together at the end of summer,
この公園で見つけた あの星座 何だか覚えてる？
in this park we found that constellation... Do you remember what it was?
会えなくても 記憶をたどって
Even if we can't meet, I trace my memories,
同じ幸せを見たいんだ
wanting to see that same happiness.
あの香りとともに 花火がぱっと開く
Along with that scent, the fireworks burst open.
行きたいよ 君のところへ 今すぐかけだして 行きたいよ
I want to go to where you are. I want to run to you right now.
まっ暗で 何も見えない 怖くても大丈夫
It's pitch black and I can't see anything. I'm scared, but I'll be okay.
数えきれない星空が 今もずっとここにあるんだよ
The sky with countless stars is still right here, always.
泣かないよ 昔君と見た きれいな空だったから
I won't cry, because the sky we saw together back then was so beautiful.
あの道まで響く 靴の音が耳に残る
The sound of shoes echoing down that road remains in my ears.
大きな自分の影を 見つめて想うのでしょう
Staring at my own large shadow, I wonder what you're thinking.
ちっとも変わらないはずなのに せつない気持ちふくらんでく
Nothing should have changed at all, yet this painful feeling swells.
どんなに想ったって 君はもういない
No matter how much I think of you, you're not here anymore.
行きたいよ 君のそばに 小さくても小さくても
I want to go to your side, even if I'm small, even if I'm small.
1番に君が好きだよ 強くいられる
You're the one I love the most, so I can stay strong.
願いを流れ星に そっと唱えてみたけれど
I softly whispered a wish to a shooting star, but...
泣かないよ 届くだろう きれいな空に
I won't cry, it will surely reach that beautiful sky.
会えなくても 記憶をたどって
Even if we can't meet, I trace my memories,
同じ幸せを見たいんだ
wanting to see that same happiness.
あの香りとともに 花火がぱっと開く
Along with that scent, the fireworks burst open.
行きたいよ 君のところへ
I want to go to where you are,
小さな手をにぎりしめて
tightly holding your small hand.
泣きたいよ それはそれは
I want to cry, it was, it was...
きれいな空だった
such a beautiful sky.
願いを 流れ星に
I quietly made a wish on a shooting star,
そっと唱えて みたけれど
but even so...
泣きたいよ 届かない
I want to cry; my feelings won't reach...
想いを この空に…
my feelings to this sky...
イェーイ！ ありがとう！
Yay! Thank you!
すごい ハイタッチ！ ハイタッチまじ！
Wow, high five! High five, seriously!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ごめん！
Sorry!
ちょっと形いい感じになった
That actually turned out pretty cool!
はい プラネタリウムでした！
Alright, that was "Planetarium"!
やったー！
Yay!
もうこれライブパフォーマンスやん マジで！
That was straight up a live performance, seriously!
最高すぎるやろ！
That was way too awesome!
もう一回聞きたい！
I wanna hear it again!
あの 体力がないですね
Well, I don't have the stamina for that.
あ そっか 体力かー
Ah, right, stamina...
えー じゃあ奏 歌う？ 一緒に
Eh, then Kanade, wanna sing? Together!
えー！ 嫌だ！ 歌いたい！
Eh?! No way! I wanna sing!
なんの… 何歌う？
What... What should we sing?
もうあの曲行っちゃいますか！
Shall we just go with that song?!
お！ 何々？
Ooh! What is it?
やっぱお星様がキラキラしたら もう一回キラキラしていいんじゃないのー？
Since the stars shone so brightly, shouldn't we shine bright once more?
プラネタリウムから外出ちゃう？
Heading outside from the planetarium?
それー！
That's the one!
何の曲かな〜？
What song could it be~?
じゃあ行きましょう！ お願いしまーす！
Alright, let me cue it up! Here we go!
どっちからだっけ？ え、どっちからだっけ？
Who starts first? Wait, who goes first?
午前二時 フミキリに
At 2:00 a.m. at the railroad crossing,
望遠鏡を 担いでった
I carried my telescope on my shoulder.
ベルトに 結んだ ラジオ
With a radio tied to my belt,
雨は 降らないらしい
it seemed it wouldn't rain.
二分後に 君が来た
Two minutes later, you arrived,
大袈裟な 荷物 しょってきた
carrying an exaggerated amount of luggage.
始めようか 天体観測
Shall we begin our astronomical observation,
ほうき星を 探して
searching for a shooting star?
深い闇に 飲まれないように
We tried our hardest not to be swallowed
精一杯だった
by the deep darkness.
君の 震える 手を
On that day when I tried to hold
握ろうとした あの日は
your trembling hand,
見えないモノを 見ようとして
I peered through the telescope,
望遠鏡を 覗き込んだ
trying to see the invisible.
静寂を 切り裂いて
Tearing through the silence,
いくつも 声が 生まれたよ
numerous voices were born.
明日が 僕らを 呼んだって
Even if tomorrow called out to us,
返事も ろくに しなかった
we barely bothered to reply.
「イマ」という ほうき星
We were chasing the shooting star called "Now",
君と 二人 追いかけていた
just the two of us.
気が付けば いつだって ひたすら 何か 探している
Before I knew it, I'm always endlessly searching for something,
幸せの 定義とか
like the definition of happiness
哀しみの 置き場とか
or where sadness belongs.
生まれたら 死ぬまで ずっと 探してる
From birth until death, I'll keep searching forever.
さぁ 始めようか 天体観測
Come on, let's begin our astronomical observation,
ほうき星を 探して
searching for a shooting star.
今まで 見つけた モノは
I remember everything
全部 覚えている
I've found up until now,
君の 震える 手を
even the pain of not being able
握れなかった 痛みも
to hold your trembling hand.
知らないモノを 知ろうとして
I peered through the telescope,
望遠鏡を 覗き込んだ
trying to know the unknown.
暗闇を 照らす様 な
I searched for a faint light
微かな 光 探したよ
that would illuminate the darkness.
そうして 知った 痛みを
I still remember
未だに 僕は 覚えている
the pain I came to know back then.
「イマ」という ほうき星
I am still chasing the shooting star called "Now"
今も 一人 追いかけている
all by myself.
背が 伸びるにつれて
As I grew taller,
伝えたい 事も 増えてった
the things I wanted to communicate increased as well.
宛名の 無い 手紙も
Letters without addressees piled up
崩れる程 重なった
until they were on the verge of collapsing.
僕は 元気でいるよ
I am doing well,
心配事も 少ないよ
and I don't have many worries.
ただ ひとつ 今も 思い出すよ
There is just one thing I still remember:
予報外れの 雨に 打たれて
That day when we were caught in an unexpected rain
泣きだしそうな
and looked like we might start crying,
君の 震える 手を
when I couldn't hold
握れなかった あの日を
your trembling hand.
見えてる モノを 見落として
Overlooking what was right in front of my eyes,
望遠鏡を また 担いで
I hoisted my telescope once again,
静寂と 暗闇の
and ran through the way home
帰り道を 駆け抜けた
of silence and darkness.
そうして知った痛みが
And that pain I came to know
未だに 僕を支えている
is still supporting me today.
「イマ」というほうき星
"NOW" is a shooting star
今も一人追いかけている
I'm still chasing alone.
もう一度君に会おうとして
Trying to meet you once again,
望遠鏡をまた担いで
I shoulder the telescope once more,
前と同じ午前二時
at 2 a.m. just like before,
フミキリまで駆けてくよ
and run to the railroad crossing.
始めようか 天体観測
Shall we begin stargazing?
二分後に君が来なくとも
Even if you don't come in two minutes,
「イマ」というほうき星
"NOW" is a shooting star
君と二人追いかけている
that you and I are chasing together.
なんか、すごく疲れた...
Man, I'm so exhausted...
めっちゃ踊ってくれた...
You guys danced so much for us...
踊ってたっていうかパフォーマンス？
Was that dancing, or more like a performance?
体が勝手に...
My body just moved on its own...
2人でね、呼吸を合わせに行ってたんだよね
The two of us were trying to get in sync, right?
ああ疲れたね
Ah, I'm so tired.
めっちゃ歩き回っちゃった
I ended up walking around so much.
歩き回ってたね
You really were walking around!
全員ちょっとヘトヘト...
Everyone is a bit worn out...
1曲目からもうヘトヘトですけれども
Even though it's only the first song, we're already exhausted.
でもね、このままちょっとらでんと番長の2人の歌も聴きたいなーなんて思ってるんですけれども
But still, I'd love to hear Raden and Bancho sing next!
聴きたい！
We want to hear it!
聴きたいじゃなくて、チャリで駆け上がりますか！
Instead of just listening, shall we race up on bikes?
チャリで、行きますか！
On bikes? Let's go!
行ってきてください！
Go for it!
準備いいですか？
Are you ready?
じゃあ、音楽お願いします！
Okay, music please!
夏色！
Natsuiro!
夏と言えば夏色や！
When you think of summer, it's Natsuiro!
チャリンチャリンチャリンチャリン...
Ring-ding-ding-ding...
駐車場のネコは アクビをしながら
The cat in the parking lot yawns
今日も一日を過ごしてゆく
as it spends another day.
何も変わらない 穏やかな街並
Nothing changes in this peaceful streetscape.
みんな夏が来たって 浮かれ気分なのに
Everyone is excited that summer has come,
君は一人さえな顔してるネ
yet you alone look downcast.
そうだ君に 見せたい物があるんだ
That's right, there's something I want to show you:
大きな五時半の夕やけ
A grand sunset at 5:30,
子供の頃と同じように
just like when we were kids.
海も空も雲も 僕等でさえも 染めてゆくから...
It dyes the sea, sky, clouds, and even us...
この長い長い下り坂を 君を自転車の後ろに乗せて
Carrying you on the back of my bicycle down this long, long downhill slope,
ブレーキいっぱい 握りしめて
squeezing the brakes as tight as I can,
ゆっくりゆっくり下ってく
we slowly, slowly go down.
下って行こう！
Let's go down!
風鈴の音で ウトウトしながら
Dozing off to the sound of wind chimes,
夢見ごこちで ヨダレをたらしてる
drooling in a dreamlike daze.
Woh... いつもと同じ 網戸ごしの風の匂い
Woh... The same scent of wind through the screen door as always.
休日でみんなも ゴロゴロしてるのに
Even though everyone is lazing around on their day off,
君はずいぶん 忙しい顔をしてるネ
you've got such a busy look on your face.
そうだいつかの あの場所へ行こう
That's right, let's go to that place from back then.
真夏の夜の波の音は
The sound of midsummer night waves
不思議な程心 静かになる
calms the heart to a mysterious degree.
少しだけ全て忘れて
Forgetting everything just for a moment,
波の音の中 包みこまれていく
we get wrapped up in the sound of the waves.
この細い細い うら道を抜けて
Passing through this narrow, narrow side alley,
誰もいない大きな 夜の海見ながら
looking at the vast, deserted night sea,
線香花火に 二人で
the two of us together
ゆっくりゆっくり 火をつける
slowly, slowly light up sparklers.
いつか君の涙が こぼれおちそうになったら
If your tears ever threaten to spill over someday,
何もしてあげられないけど
though there's nothing I can really do for you,
少しでもそばにいるよ...
I'll be by your side as much as I can...
この長い長い下り坂を 君を自転車の後ろに乗せて
Carrying you on the back of my bicycle down this long, long downhill slope,
ブレーキいっぱい 握りしめて
squeezing the brakes as tight as I can,
ゆっくりゆっくり下ってく
we slowly, slowly go down,
slowly, slowly go down,
ゆっくりゆっくり下ってく
slowly, slowly go down.
夏だね！
It's summer!
夏が始まった！
Summer has started!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
にゃー
Meow!
じゃあ、ちょっと連続なんですけど
Well, it's back-to-back songs, but...
あら
Oh my.
最後4人で歌いたいと思います！
We'd like to sing together with all four of us at the end!
おー！
Yay!
何歌うんですか？
What are you going to sing?
何歌うんだろうね？
I wonder what we're singing?
じゃあ皆さん聴いてください！おねがいします！
Everyone, please listen! Here we go!
おねがいします！
Here we go!
ウィーアー！
We Are!
誰が言う？誰が言う？
Who says it? Who says it?
冷静に！冷静に！
Calm down! Calm down!
富、名声、力、この世のすべてを手に入れた男、海賊王ゴールド・ロジャー。
Wealth, fame, power... The man who acquired everything this world had to offer, the Pirate King, Gold Roger.
彼の死に際に放った一言は、人々を海に駆り立てた。
His dying words drove people to the seas.
「俺の財宝か？欲しけりゃくれたる！探せ！この世のすべてをそこに置いてきた！」
"My treasure? If you want it, you can have it! Find it! I left everything this world has to offer in that place!"
男たちはグランドラインを目指し、夢を追い続ける。世はまさに、大海賊時代！
Men headed for the Grand Line, chasing their dreams. The world is truly in the Great Pirate Era!
ありったけの夢を かき集め
Gathering up all the pieces of our dreams
捜し物を 探しに行くのさ
We're going to search for everything we're looking for
One Piece
羅針盤なんて 渋滞のもと
A compass will only cause traffic jams
熱にうかされ 舵をとるのさ
Feverish with excitement, I take the helm
ホコリかぶってた 宝の地図も
Even a dusty old treasure map
確かめたのなら 伝説じゃない！
If you verify it, it's not a legend!
個人的な嵐は 誰かの
A personal storm is just riding
バイオリズム乗っかって 思い過ごせばいい！
someone else's biorhythm—don't overthink it!
ありったけの夢を かき集め
Gathering up all the pieces of our dreams
捜し物を 探しに行くのさ
We're going to search for everything we're looking for
ポケットのコイン それと You wanna be my Friend?
A coin in the pocket, and You wanna be my Friend?
We are, We are on the cruise! ウィーアー！
We are, We are on the cruise! We Are!
ウィーアー！
We Are!
ぜんぶまに受けて 信じちゃっても
Even if you take everything to heart and believe it
肩を押されて 1歩リードさ
Getting pushed on the shoulder gives you a one-step lead
今度会えたなら 話すつもりさ
If we ever meet again, I plan to talk about
それからのことと これからのこと
what happened since then and what comes next
つまりいつも ピンチは誰かに
In other words, a pinch is always
アピール出来るいいチャンス 自意識過剰に！
a great chance to make an impression—over-self-consciously!
しみったれた夜を ぶっとばせ！
Blow away the gloomy nights!
宝箱にキョウミはないけど
I have no interest in treasure chests, but...
ポケットにロマン それと You wanna be my Friend?
A romance in the pocket, and You wanna be my Friend?
We are, We are on the cruise! ウィーアー！
We are, We are on the cruise! We Are!
ありったけの夢を かき集め
Gathering up all the pieces of our dreams
捜し物を 探しに行くのさ
We're going to search for everything we're looking for
ポケットのコイン それと You wanna be my Friend? / We are, We are on the cruise!
A coin in the pocket, and You wanna be my Friend? / We are, We are on the cruise!
ウィーアー！ ウィーアー！ ウィーアー！
We Are! We Are! We Are!
イエーイ！
Yay!
やばい、もう時間だ！最後に知らせがあります！
Oh no, time is almost up! We have an announcement at the end!
あっという間だ！
That flew by so fast!
改めてになりますが、明日0時、つまり今日の24時に...
Once again, tomorrow at 0:00, meaning 24:00 tonight...
「Midsummer Citrus」がデジタル配信リリースされます！
"Midsummer Citrus" will be released digitally!
こちら各種配信サイトで聴けるようになります！
It will be available on various music streaming services!
うん！
Yep!
そして来月の配信なんですが、いつも10日にReGLOSSのこの配信やってるんですけれど...
And regarding next month's stream, we usually do this ReGLOSS stream on the 10th, but...
8月は8月1日に配信予定となっておりますので、間違えないように注意してください！
for August, it's scheduled for August 1st, so please be careful not to mistake it!
1日！日付が変わった瞬間、よろしくね！
The 1st! The moment the date changes, please join us!
よろしくお願いします！楽しかったね、カラオケ！
Thank you! Karaoke was so much fun!
カラオケとは思えない...
Hard to believe it was just karaoke...
誰も動かないけどね
Though nobody's moving.
全力でした！
We gave it our all!
美味しいもの食べるぞー！
Time to eat something delicious!
見てくれたみんなも楽しんでくれたかな？
I hope everyone who watched had fun too!
楽しかったー！
It was so much fun!
たくさんのアンケートのご回答も...
Thank you so much for answering...
ありがとうございました！
...all of our survey questions!
じゃあ今日はこんなところで終わりますか！
Alright, shall we wrap things up here for today?
はい！
Yeah!
それではまた来月お会いしましょう！見てくれてありがとうね！
See you again next month! Thanks for watching!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
新曲披露もあるよ♪ 真夏のReGLOSSカラオケ
[New Song Reveal Too! Midsummer ReGLOSS Karaoke]